<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
	<title>Restiffbard</title>
	<subtitle>the digital diatribes of Christopher Cabanillas</subtitle>
	<link href="atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
	<link href="" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
	<id></id>
	<updated>2011-04-23T11:31:48-04:00</updated>
	<author>
		<name>C.R. Cabanillas</name>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Reconstruction</title>
			<link href="/reconstruction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
			<updated>2011-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
			<id>/reconstruction</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;#8217;s been some time since I was active at this&amp;#8230; url. That&amp;#8217;s changing but part of that change is a complete rebuild of the site. This has more to do with the backend than it does with the front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, sure, this page doesn&amp;#8217;t quite look like what you might remember but the text.css is exactly the same. So&amp;#8230;well&amp;#8230; there&amp;#8217;s that. Once everything is in proper working order I&amp;#8217;ll do a more detailed &amp;#8220;what the heck did I do&amp;#8221; post. Till then I&amp;#8217;ll just say it&amp;#8217;s Jekyll and Markdown and super simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime expect that when I have a spare day I&amp;#8217;ll be working on the CSS and various other layout bits here and there and generally making things spiffy again.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Hanna, a review</title>
			<link href="/hanna-a-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
			<updated>2011-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
			<id>/hanna-a-review</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1519680/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Saoirse Ronan&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0993842/' title='Hanna at IMDB'&gt;Hanna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Not knowing if there was ever another contender for the role you can&amp;#8217;t imagine anyone else playing this character. Raised in the forest to be something of a killing machine she is set to avenge her mother&amp;#8217;s murder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, that&amp;#8217;s all the plot you really need know. Normally I&amp;#8217;d tip-toe around spoilers but there&amp;#8217;s no need. &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000949/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Cate Blanchett&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s character is bad. Saoirse&amp;#8217;s (I&amp;#8217;m enjoying trying to remember how to spell that name) character is out for revenge because that&amp;#8217;s what she&amp;#8217;s been raised to do. Plot, done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason to see the film is more about the way in which this story we&amp;#8217;ve all read or seen before is presented. &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0942504/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Joe Wright&lt;/a&gt; previously directed Saoirse in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0783233/' title='Atonement at IMDB'&gt;Atonement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, a very different tragedy-romance period film set against a World War II backdrop. Hanna is not his sort of story and he reportedly only took the job because Saoirse told him to. Lucky for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the assassin nature of the character Wright focuses more on her reaction to the world around her than her fighting prowess. Often fight scenes are flurries of jump cuts resulting in a pile of bodies. Far more interest is shown the first time Hanna encounters a fluorescent light fixture and does battle with an electric kettle. Wright does a wonderful job of creating lovely scenes in snow and desert and cramped camper vans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saoirse is brilliant at doing the child-like wonder thing and then switching instantly to the psychopathic murderess thing. She&amp;#8217;s also quite the runner. I imagine she spent a great amount of time out of breath on set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0051509/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Eric Bana&lt;/a&gt; manages to be &amp;#8220;Eric Bana&amp;#8221; without getting in the way of the real star, Saoirse, being Hanna. I can think of a few other actors that would have failed at this simple task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cate Blanchett is an actor I adore in anything she does. Cate could sit in a chair reading a telephone directory and be certain of my rapt attention. Cate manages to be a woman while doing traditionally evil male things. That may sound silly but I&amp;#8217;ve found it rare that any evil female character is portrayed as anything other than a man in a woman&amp;#8217;s skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to mention the accents now. Saoirse is Irish. Blanchett and Bana are both Aussies. If you&amp;#8217;d never seen them in another film before this one you wouldn&amp;#8217;t believe me. Saoirse&amp;#8217;s talent for accent is admirable. I&amp;#8217;m afraid, though, that Cate&amp;#8217;s use of a southern American drawl is an exaggerated mask and from time to time you can hear her falling out of it. Bana could probably apply for German citizenship and no one would bat an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re well into an age now where talking about a film without talking about the soundtrack would be only half a review. The Chemical Brothers have created a score as frenzied, jarring, and lovely (in equal parts) as the film itself. There are, of course, beeps and bloops and other electronic bits scattered among the thumping beats but there are also serene lullabic pieces as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering my recent re-viewing of last years &lt;em&gt;Tron Legacy&lt;/em&gt; and the frequency with which Daft Punk&amp;#8217;s soundtrack for that film appears in my playlist I can&amp;#8217;t help but compare. Each fits the film they accompany but Daft Punk&amp;#8217;s Tron is more likely to get play time than will the Chemical Brothers&amp;#8217; Hanna. That said, I think that if you already enjoy the Chemical Brothers as I do then you&amp;#8217;d be happy to add this soundtrack to your library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I have to say a word for the foley artist. The ambient sound in this film plays such a huge role. I can&amp;#8217;t divide the film into equal parts of directing, sound design, acting, etcetera but not to mention the impact of incidental sound in Hanna would be a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the film. I think that if you&amp;#8217;re interested in seeing a pretty girl eviscerate a grown man then you will as well. Just don&amp;#8217;t go expecting to see blood and guts at every turn. This isn&amp;#8217;t that film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanna, April 2011 Starring: &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1519680/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Saoirse Ronan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000949/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Cate Blanchett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0051509/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Eric Bana&lt;/a&gt; Director: &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0942504/' title='IMDB profile'&gt;Joe Wright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Once More Unto The Breach Dear Friends</title>
			<link href="/once-more-unto-the-breach-dear-friends/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
			<updated>2011-03-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
			<id>/once-more-unto-the-breach-dear-friends</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been quite a while since I was active on the web. There have been tweets but it hasn&amp;#8217;t been the same. On a number of occasions I wanted to say something but didn&amp;#8217;t simply because 140 characters just wasn&amp;#8217;t enough. I kept mum. Frankly, it doesn&amp;#8217;t matter if you missed my additions to the cacophony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I missed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='i_am_the_content'&gt;I am the content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, even at my most gregarious, I held back on certain types of posts because of a concern that my readers were uninterested in this or that topic. I had an idea who my readers were and I catered very carefully to them. This would often lead to dry spells when my attention wandered to areas far off the path that restiffbard.com had beaten out for itself. If I was suddenly interested in something I didn&amp;#8217;t feel my audience would care about then posting would slow or simply stop for weeks or months at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That won&amp;#8217;t be the case for this go-round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='where_things_stand'&gt;where things stand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a clean slate. If you&amp;#8217;re looking for old entries you simply won&amp;#8217;t find them. They exist. They&amp;#8217;re in a file backed up somewhere. They&amp;#8217;re just not here. If you&amp;#8217;re reading this the day I&amp;#8217;m posting it then the appearance of this page is stock Wordpress. That&amp;#8217;ll change one can assume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m rusty. I&amp;#8217;ve not kept up to date. I know there is an HTML 5. I have no idea if/how/what/why to do anything with that. I&amp;#8217;m older. I have to jog my memory by looking at old template files from previous incarnations of restiffbard.com and glean what I can from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve bounced around from one CMS to another. Wordpress, Drupal, ExpressionEngine, and others whose names I can&amp;#8217;t recall. They&amp;#8217;ve been written in PHP, Perl, Ruby. They&amp;#8217;ve all had their own way of templating things and it&amp;#8217;s all a jumble in my head now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will take some time to work out the kinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='what_is_to_come'&gt;what is to come&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More. Look for commentary on the web and Apple and Google and others. That I&amp;#8217;ve always done. Look for tips and tricks. I&amp;#8217;ve done a spot of that in the past as well. Also, look for me talking about games. I&amp;#8217;d always talked about music and film in the past but I left out my baser addiction to games. It wasn&amp;#8217;t for this audience. I forgot that I was a member of that audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll also talk more about my writing. I not only write these bits here but I, like nearly everyone else, have authorial aspirations. I need to talk about that too. Whole worlds live in my head and I&amp;#8217;d like to offer you a peak at them if only to be able to get away, for one more day, with being completely insane and yet not in an asylum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='what_have_we_learned'&gt;what have we learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, I&amp;#8217;m back. Though I was never really gone. I had been creeping about on the periphery. It&amp;#8217;s high time I stepped back on the stage. I&amp;#8217;ve also forgotten some things. I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten some markup, some styling. My memory will get me lost poking around the innards of a template these days. The most important thing I forgot, though, was the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forgot I&amp;#8217;m a blogger.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
 
</feed>
